Finding Aid for Nathan W. Shock Papers 1906-1989
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Nathan W. Shock Papers
1906-1989
1927-1988
Shock, Nathan Wetherill, 1906-
Gerontologist; series in collection include: Biography and Early Career; Lectures, Speeches, Publications; History of Gerontology; Correspondence; Gerontology Research Center Files; Conferences; Foundations; International Association of Gerontology (IAG); International Organizations; Gerontological Society of America; Other Organizations; Audio tapes; and Photographs.
921099 Aa 2
50 linear feet
1 oversize folders
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The papers of Nathan W. Shock were transferred from the Institute of Gerontology, University of Michigan (donor no. 6160 ) in 1989, 1990, and 1991.
The collection is open for research.
Nathan Wetherill Shock, a renowned gerontologist, was born in Lafayette, Indiana on December 25, 1906, the son of Blanche Vandelia Stults, a grade school teacher, and Joseph Henry Shock, a teacher of mathematics, high school principal, and later professor of mathematics at Purdue University. Nathan Shock grew up in Lafayette, received a degree in chemical engineering from Purdue in 1926, and the master's degree in organic chemistry the following year. In 1928 Shock married Margaret B. Truman, a Lafayette resident. In 1930 Shock received a Ph.D. in physiological psychology at the University of Chicago and stayed on as a research associate in the pediatrics department while teaching physiology for two years.
In 1932 Shock went to the University of California, Berkeley, as research associate in the Institute of Child Welfare and assistant professor in physiology, staying until 1941. It was at Berkeley that he learned the value of performing longitudinal studies of humans to assess changes over time in a group of 100 boys and girls who were followed from age 10 to 18 years. Measurement of physiologic changes in infants at the University of Chicago became measurement of changes in adolescents at the University of California, and at the Gerontology Research Center in Baltimore became measurement of physiologic change over time in groups of elderly subjects.
The United States National Institutes of Health (NIH) at Bethesda, Maryland began its interest in aging studies in 1940, and in October of 1941 Shock was called to head the new gerontology unit, with a research facility within the Baltimore City Hospitals. In the late 1940s NIH organized its research programs as institutes with category labels, and the Section on Aging became first a part of the National Heart Institute, was transferred to the National Institute of Child Health and Development and in 1975 the gerontology program became part of the National Institute on Aging; Dr. Shock was named Scientific Director of the new institute and continued his research studies until his retirement in 1977. Then, as Scientist Emeritus, he continued his studies and writings until his death on November 12, 1989 at the age of 82.
Nathan Shock, a man of great organizational abilities, was instrumental in the development and growth of major gerontological societies nationally and internationally. He served as president of the Gerontological Society of America (1960-1961), president of the International Association of Gerontology (1969 to 1972), and editor-in-chief of the Journal of Gerontology.
His most notable contribution to the emerging discipline of gerontology was in the Baltimore Longitudinal Study of Aging. The author of several books, he also contributed more than 200 articles to the scientific literature on gerontology. He was the recipient of numerous awards and honors in his chosen field. Many characterized Nathan Shock as the father of American gerontology.
Dr. Shock had a keen interest in the history of gerontology and sought to preserve the important documents of the field in his papers.
Summary Contents List
Biography and Early Career--Boxes 1-3
Lectures, Speeches, Publications--Boxes 3-5
History of Gerontology--Boxes 5-6
Correspondence--Boxes 7-10
Gerontology Research Center, 1940-1978--Boxes 11-28
Baltimore Longitudinal Study of Aging--Boxes 21-24
Center for Aging Research--Boxes 24-25
Baltimore City Hospitals--Boxes 25-26
Building Records--Boxes 26-27
National Institute on Aging--Boxes 27-28
Conferences--Boxes 28-30
Foundations--Boxes 30-31
International Association of Gerontology--Boxes 31-35
International Organizations-Other--Box 35
Gerontological Society of America--Boxes 35-40
Other Organizations--Boxes 40-44
Photographs--Box 44
Audio Tapes--Boxes 45-50
The papers of Nathan Wetherill Shock, with bulk dates of 1927 to 1988, measure fifty linear feet. They are divided into thirteen series: Biography and Early Career; Lectures, Speeches, Publications; History of Gerontology; Correspondence; Gerontology Research Center Files; Conferences; Foundations; International Association of Gerontology (IAG); International Organizations-Other; Gerontological Society of America (GSA); Other Organizations; Photographs; and Audio Tapes.
Subjects:
Aging.; Gerontological Society of America.; Gerontology.; Gerontology Research Center (U. S.); International Association of Gerontology.; National Institute on Aging.; National Institutes of Health (U. S.). Center for Aging Research.; Shock, Nathan W. (Nathan Wetherill), 1906-1989
Subjects - Visual Material:
Gerontological Society of America.; Gerontology.; Gerontology Research Center (U. S.); International Association of Gerontology.; Shock, Nathan W. (Nathan Wetherill), 1906-1989
Genre/Form:
Photographs.
- Biography and Early Career
  Biography and Early Career (2.5 linear feet) covers the personal life, education, and early professional appointments of Shock. Here, also, is included information on honors and awards from his long career. The first folder contains transcripts of interviews and his autobiographies; these are helpful to the researcher in assessing his philosophy about gerontology, and for his articulate descriptions of the development of aging research within the federal government.
  - Biographies and interviews (Box 1)
  - Birth certificate (Box 1)
  - Bibliography, 1927-1985 (Box 1)
  - Curriculum vitae, to, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Nathan Shock's notes on his archival files (Box 1)
  - Early years (Box 1)
  - Thesis, Master of Science, Purdue University, 1927 (Box 1)
  - Biographical Directories listings (Box 1)
  - Visitors signature book, 1946-1968 (Box 1)
  - Diary, professional, 1942-1948 (Box 1)
  - Career appointments, 1930-1976 (Box 1)
  - Honors, awards, testimonials, 1951-1983 (Box 1)
  - Honors, 35th anniversary with NIH, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Scientist Emeritus and retirement, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Eightieth birthday celebration, 1986-1987 (Box 1)
  - Experimental Gerontology [Festschrift honoring Shock on his eightieth birthday] (Box 1)
  - Medals (Box 1)
  - Shock, Margaret (Box 1)
  - Shock residence, Idlewild, Maryland (Box 1)
  - University of Chicago dissertation, 1st part, June 1930 (Box 1)
  - University of Chicago, dissertation, 2nd part (Box 2)
  - University of California
    - Correspondence, A-J, 1935-1940 (Box 2)
    - Correspondence, K-Z, 1935-1940 (Box 2)
    - Adolescent studies, 1938 (Box 2)
    - Adolescent studies, budgets, 1935-1940 (Box 2)
    - Research proposal, Physiological changes in adolescence, 1938 (Box 2)
    - Physiology course lecture notes, 1940 (Box 2)
    - Physiology course outline, 1958 (Box 2)
    - Institute of Human Development, report, 1958-1959 (Box 2)
    - Blood pressure studies (Box 2)
    - Physiology of growth and development of child, course, 1941 (Box 2)
    - Project, developmental changes in rate of recovery from physiological displacements, 1934-1939; 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Galvanometer testing schedules, 1933-1937 (Box 2)
    - Galvanometer testing schedules, 1938-1941 (Box 2)
    - Galvanometer testing schedules, case descriptions, 1933-1935 (Box 2)
    - Galvanometer testing schedules, case descriptions, 1936-1941 (Box 3)
    - Physiological changes in adolescence, summary curves and drawings, 1941 (Box 3)
    - Adolescence studies, raw data, 1933-1941 (Box 3)
    - Adolescence studies, retesting, 1956-1962 (Box 3)
- Lectures, speeches, publications
  The series Lectures, Speeches, Publications (2 linear feet) is self explanatory.
  - Lectures, speeches
    - 1946-1951 (Box 3)
    - 1954-1956 (Box 3)
    - 1954-1970 (Box 3)
      (University of Maryland)
    - 1959-1962 (Box 3)
    - 1964 (Box 3)
    - 1966 (Box 3)
    - Others, not Shock, 1966 (Box 3)
    - 1967-1969 (Box 3)
    - 1970 (Box 3)
    - 1971, 2 folders (Box 3)
    - 1973, 3 folders (Box 3)
    - 1974-1975 (Box 4)
    - 1976 (Box 4)
    - 1977 (Box 4)
    - 1978-1979 (Box 4)
    - 1980 (Box 4)
    - 1980-1981 (Box 4)
      (pre-retirement seminars, Johns Hopkins University)
    - 1981 (Box 4)
    - 1982 (Box 4)
    - 1984 (Box 4)
    - 1984 (Box 4)
      (Workshop on Research Needs in Hypertension and Aging)
    - 1984 (Box 4)
      (Meharry Medical College)
    - 1987 (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous (NFI) (Box 4)
  - Publications (including manuscripts)
    - Data for manuscripts and publications (University of California) (Box 4)
    - Manuscripts submitted, 1938-1941; 3 folders (Box 4)
    - Manuscript (publication uncertain) Physiology of Adolescence, 1940-1943; 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Manuscript (publication uncertain), Kushner book, Chapter IV (Box 4)
    - Manuscript (publication uncertain), "The physiological basis of aging", 1982 (Box 4)
    - Manuscripts refereed by N. W. Shock (sampled) (Box 5)
    - Book reviews prepared by N.W, Shock (Box 5)
    - Trends in Gerontology, 1951 (Box 5)
    - A Classified Bibliography of Gerontology and Geriatrics, 1951 (Box 5)
    - Book reviews of Trends in Gerontology and A Classified Bibliography of Gerontology and Geriatrics (Box 5)
    - Current List of Publications in Gerontology and Geriatrics, 1968; 1975 (Box 5)
    - International Research Monographs, 1972-1974 (Box 5)
    - "Physiological and chronological age", 1980 (Box 5)
    - Human Biology and Pathology, 1984 (Box 5)
    - "Longitudinal studies on the rate of decline in renal function with age", 1984 (Box 5)
    - Encyclopedia of Aging, 1985 (Box 5)
    - Aging of the Kidney, 1986 (Box 5)
    - Food, Drugs and Aging, 1986 (Box 5)
    - "The evolution of gerontology as a science", 1986 (Box 5)
    - Review of Biological Research, Volume 3, 1987 (Box 5)
- History of Gerontology
  Dr. Shock assembled most of the material in the series History of Gerontology (2.5 linear feet) and additional material was added during processing. Shock's writings on the history of gerontology are included here. His long-standing interest in preserving archival material is evidenced in the early folders of this series.
  - Archives of gerontology, 1967-1979 (Box 5)
  - Archives of gerontology, 1980-1984 (Box 5)
  - Archives of gerontology, 1988 (Box 5)
  - History of Gerontology-chronology, 1938-1987 (Box 5)
  - National Advisory Committee on Gerontology, United States Public Health Service, remarks by Surgeon General Thomas Parran at first meeting of Committee, November 25, 1940 (Box 5)
  - Bibliography of publications of the Gerontology Research Center, 1940-1975 (Box 5)
  - Steele, Murray, "The problem of the process of aging", circa 1940 (Box 5)
  - History of the field of aging-plan for a geriatric society, 1941 (Box 5)
  - "Gerontology and geriatrics", a symposium Modern Medicine, January 1941 (Box 5)
  - Steiglitz, E.J., "Report of a survey of active studies in gerontology", 1942 (Box 5)
  - Organization charts, functions of the Gerontology Research Center, 1946; 1956-1968 (Box 5)
  - National Institutes of Health, Division of Research Grants, Physiology Study Section, 1946-1978 (Box 5)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1946-1981 (Box 5)
  - United States Public Health Service, Gerontology Study Section, 1947 (Box 5)
  - Conference on the planning of the research hospital, National Institutes of Health, September 19, 1947 (Box 5)
    (N.W. Shock's notes, hospital plans, correspondence, 1947-1948)
  - European and American societies for research on aging, 1947-1961 (Box 5)
  - Social Science Research Council, Committee on Social Adjustments in Old Age, "Memorandum on research in progress on social science aspects of old age", February 1948 (Box 5)
  - United States Public Health Service, conference on aging, October 11, 1950 (Box 5)
  - Josiah Macy, Jr. Foundation, history, 1950; 1977 (Box 5)
  - United States Administration on Aging, chronology, 1951-1981 (Box 5)
  - University of Kansas. Department of Gerontology. Postgraduate courses in geriatrics, 1952-1953 (Box 5)
  - Gerontological Association of Japan, 2nd Annual Report, 1957 (Box 5)
  - Baltimore City Hospitals internships, residencies, 1957; 1963 (Box 5)
  - Gerontological Society history (Box 5)
    ("Gerontology--a multiple disciplinary science; the future of the Gerontological Society", N.W. Shock, October 1979 "History of Gerontological Society, Inc.", M. Adler, 1958)
  - American Medical Association, Committee on Aging, "A new concept of aging; a hearing on its implications for medicine", 1960 (Box 5)
  - Gerontology Research Center, history, 1960 (Box 5)
  - Program of requirements for gerontology building, National Heart Institute, Baltimore City Hospitals April 12, 1962 revision, June 26, 1962 (Box 5)
  - Legislative history, National Institute of Child Health and Human Development, 1962-1963 (Box 5)
  - "The youthful science of aging", Knutti, R.E., 1964 (Box 5)
  - Ethel Percy Andrus Gerontology Center, University of Southern California at Los Angeles, 1964-1989 (Box 5)
  - "History of the Baltimore City Hospitals", Carroll, Douglas, 1966 (Box 6)
  - History of Gerontology Committee, International Association of Gerontology, 1966-1970 (Box 6)
  - Jahresberichte des Institutes fur Experimentelle Gerontologie, Basel, Switzerland, Annual reports, 1966-1977 (Box 6)
  - Gerontology Research Center, dedication, June 15, 1968 (Box 6)
  - "Das werden einer neuen wissenschaft", Verzar, F., 1968 (Box 6)
  - "Current Trends in biological research on aging", Shock, N.W., 1968 (Box 6)
  - "History of gerontology in the United States", Kaplan, O.J., 1969 (Box 6)
  - National Institutes of Health-Baltimore City Hospitals, memorandum of understanding, 1972 (Box 6)
  - "Kiev to Kiev in gerontology, 1938-1972", Freeman, J.T., 1973 (Box 6)
  - National Council of Senior Citizens, chronology, 1973-1974 (Box 6)
  - "History of gerontology", Birren, J.E. and Clayton, V., 1975 (Box 6)
  - National Institute of Child Health and Human Development, history, 1977 (Box 6)
  - "Edmund Vincent Cowdry (1888-1972): One of Gerontology's shoulders", Freeman, J.T., 1978 (Box 6)
  - "Tracing the historical growth of gerontology as a discipline", Oliver, D.B. and Eckerman, J.M., 1979 (Box 6)
  - National Institute on Aging, history, Freeman, J.T., 1979 (Box 6)
  - "Historical perspectives on aging", Shock, N.W., Dill Symposium, May 15-18, 1979 (Box 6)
  - "Reflections on the emergence of gerontology", Shock, N.W., May 29, 1980 (Box 6)
  - Cayo Santiago Primate Colony, 1980 (Box 6)
  - "NCOA thirty years 1950-1980". National Council on the Aging (Box 6)
  - "The National Institute on Aging: A legislative and administrative history", Kawecki, C., May 25, 1980 (Box 6)
  - "The politics of aging research", Locket, B., 1980 (Box 6)
  - American Public Health Association, Gerontological Health Section, 1980-1981 (Box 6)
  - American Geriatrics Society, report to the Board of Directors, April 15, 1980 (Box 6)
  - "Historical development of gerontology", Shock, N.W., 1981 (Box 6)
  - White House Conference on Aging, 1981 (Box 6)
  - International Association of Gerontology, history, N.W. Shock notes, 1985-1986 (Box 6)
  - Various documents on aging, unclassified (Box 6)
  - Biographies, obituaries (Box 6)
  - Papers of Clive McCay, 1934-1942
    - Laboratory studies on nutrition and animal longevity, Cornell University, 1934-1942; 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Age abstracts and letters, 1930s; 1940s (Box 6)
    - Information on aging, reviews of publications, book lists, undated; 2 folders (Box 6)
- Correspondence
  The series Correspondence (4 linear feet) is arranged alphabetically and covers the years 1934 to 1988; for unknown reasons it is heavily concentrated in the period of the mid-1970s just before his retirement from the National Institute on Aging. Other useful correspondence is found in such series as International Association of Gerontology.
  - Personal correspondence, N.W. Shock, 1934-1974 (Box 7)
  - Fan mail, 1950-1969 (Box 7)
  - Achenbaum, W.A., 1987 (Box 7)
  - Acting Clinical Director, National Institute on Aging, 1976 (Box 7)
  - Acting Director, Baltimore City Hospitals, 1976 (Box 7)
  - Acting Director, National Institute on Aging, 1976 (Box 7)
  - Adelman, R.C., 1975-1987 (Box 7)
  - Adler, M., 1971-1977 (Box 7)
  - Ajl, S., 1976 (Box 7)
  - Alvarez, W., 1958 (Box 7)
  - American College of Veterinary Pathologists, 1976 (Box 7)
  - American Dietetic Association, 1976 (Box 7)
  - American Optometric Association, 1976 (Box 7)
  - American Society for Engineering Education, 1977 (Box 7)
  - Anderson, E.E., 1976 (Box 7)
  - Andres, R., 1975-1976 (Box 7)
  - Anna T. Jeanes Foundation, 1983-1985 (Box 7)
  - Arenberg, D., 1976 (Box 7)
  - Arthur, C.S., 1985 (Box 7)
  - Aslan, A., 1958-1987 (Box 7)
  - Associate Director for Communications, National Institutes of Health, 1976 (Box 7)
  - Association for Gerontology in Higher Education, 1976 (Box 7)
  - Bagnell, P.V., 1984 (Box 7)
  - Bailliere Tindall, 1976 (Box 7)
  - Baird, M.B., 1975 (Box 7)
  - Baker, G.T., 1983-1987 (Box 7)
  - Baker, S.P., 1984 (Box 7)
  - Baliker, (n.i.), 1976 (Box 7)
  - Baltes, P.B., 1986 (Box 7)
  - Bandyopadhyay, A.K., 1976 (Box 7)
  - Banks, I.H., 1976 (Box 7)
  - Barrows, C.H., 1975-1987 (Box 7)
  - Bartus, R.T., 1980-1987 (Box 7)
  - Barzel, U.S., 1976 (Box 7)
  - Behnke, A.R., Jr., 1983 (Box 7)
  - Bell, J.G., 1976 (Box 7)
  - Bentley, D.W., 1976 (Box 7)
  - Bergman, S., 1974 (Box 7)
  - Bergmans, L., 1979 (Box 7)
  - Bhagavan, H.N., 1975 (Box 7)
  - Bierman, E.L., 1976 (Box 7)
  - Birren, J.E., 1976-1987 (Box 7)
  - Blass, J.P., 1984-1985 (Box 7)
  - Bogomolets, B.B., 1986 (Box 7)
  - Blauch, Mrs. L.E., 1974 (Box 7)
  - Bortz, W.M., II, 1983-1987 (Box 7)
  - Botwinick, J., 1984 (Box 7)
  - Boudreau, R.LK., 1976 (Box 7)
  - Bour, H., 1976 (Box 7)
  - Bourliere, F., 1971 (Box 7)
  - Brandes, D., 1974-1976 (Box 7)
  - Brandfonbrener, M., 1976 (Box 7)
  - Bray, H., 1974 (Box 7)
  - Bregman, A.A., 1976 (Box 7)
  - Britton, J., 1976 (Box 7)
  - Brock, M.A., 1976 (Box 7)
  - Brody, E.G., 1984-1985 (Box 7)
  - Brody, H., 1973-1982 (Box 7)
  - Brooker, G., 1976 (Box 7)
  - Brower, H.T., 1979 (Box 7)
  - Buetow, D.E., 1976 (Box 7)
  - Bullock, J., 1976-1977 (Box 7)
  - Burek, J.D., 1976 (Box 7)
  - Burr, W.D., 1978 (Box 7)
  - Buskey, J.H., 1983 (Box 7)
  - Buskirk, E.R., 1976 (Box 7)
  - Buss, A.R., 1979 (Box 7)
  - Busse, E.W., 1962-1987 (Box 7)
  - Butler, R.N., 1976-1985 (Box 7)
  - Butterick, J.R., 1976 (Box 7)
  - Cabarrocas, M.P., 1975 (Box 7)
  - Calabretta, C., 1974 (Box 7)
  - Carboni, D., 1976 (Box 7)
  - Cattapan, L.O., 1976 (Box 7)
  - Charles C Thomas, 1974 (Box 7)
  - Chebotarev, D.F., 1963-1988 (Box 7)
  - Chesky, J.A., 1976 (Box 7)
  - Cheville, N.F., 1976 (Box 7)
  - Chinn, A.B., 1963-1967 (Box 7)
  - Ciesla, P., 1976 (Box 7)
  - Cilento, L., 1978 (Box 7)
  - Ciuca, A., 1985 (Box 7)
  - Clayton, V., 1976 (Box 7)
  - Clerens, J., 1976 (Box 7)
  - Coco, Mrs. M., 1976 (Box 7)
  - Coffey, Mrs. W.C., 1976 (Box 7)
  - Cohen, B.J., 1976 (Box 7)
  - Cohen, E., 1975 (Box 7)
  - Cohen, G., 1976 (Box 7)
  - Cohen, S., 1976 (Box 7)
  - Cohn, V., 1975 (Box 7)
  - Cole, T., 1977 (Box 7)
  - Colucci, T.L., 1987 (Box 7)
  - Comfort, A., 1984 (Box 7)
  - Communications Officer, National Institute on Aging, Gerontology Research Center, 1976 (Box 7)
  - Contracting Officer, Grants and Contracts, National Institute of Child Health and Human Development, 1975 (Box 7)
  - Coombs, C., 1986 (Box 7)
  - Costa, P.T., Jr., 1979-1985 (Box 7)
  - Coutre, T., 1976 (Box 7)
  - Cowdry Family, 1984 (Box 7)
  - CPT Corporation, 1984-1986 (Box 7)
  - Cristofalo, V.J., 1983 (Box 7)
  - Cutler, P.G., 1988 (Box 7)
  - Cutler, R.G., 1976 (Box 7)
  - Dannefer, W.D., 1987 (Box 7)
  - Danon, D., 1974-1985 (Box 7)
  - Datan, N., 1976-1984 (Box 7)
  - Davies, D.F., 1976 (Box 7)
  - Davies, H.E.F., 1976 (Box 7)
  - Davis, P.J., 1974 (Box 7)
  - Dayton, S., 1976 (Box 7)
  - Dean, W., 1986-1988 (Box 8)
  - Deeg, D., 1988 (Box 8)
  - Denckla, W.D., 1976 (Box 8)
  - Deputy Director for Science, National Institutes of Health, 1975-1976 (Box 8)
  - Deutsche Gesellschaft fur Gerontologie, 1975 (Box 8)
  - De Vries, H.A., 1977 (Box 8)
  - Di Cara, L.V., 1976 (Box 8)
  - Dickinson, P.A., 1976 (Box 8)
  - Dill, B.D., 1974-1977 (Box 8)
  - Director, National Institute on Aging, National Institutes of Health, 1976 (Box 8)
  - Dixon, R.L., 1976 (Box 8)
  - Doberauer, W., 1984-1986 (Box 8)
  - Dr. Dietrich Steinkopff Verlag, 1976 (Box 8)
  - Donaldson, T., 1976 (Box 8)
  - Donlon, T.F., 1976 (Box 8)
  - Dontas, A.S., 1963-1982 (Box 8)
  - Dougherty, C.P., 1976 (Box 8)
  - Dufau, M.L., 1976 (Box 8)
  - Duncan, L.E., Jr., 1978 (Box 8)
  - Dunmeyer, S., 1986 (Box 8)
  - Eargle, D., 1979 (Box 8)
  - Ebert, J., 1976 (Box 8)
  - Eccles, J., 1976 (Box 8)
  - Economos, A.C., 1976-1979 (Box 8)
  - Eddy, D.E., 1976 (Box 8)
  - Editions Bailliere, 1976 (Box 8)
  - Egashira, Y., 1975 (Box 8)
  - Eichorn, G.L., 1976 (Box 8)
  - Eisdorfer, C., 1975-1988 (Box 8)
  - Eisenberg, J., 1978 (Box 8)
  - Engel, (n.i.), 1976 (Box 8)
  - Epstein, H., 1984 (Box 8)
  - Epstein, M., 1978 (Box 8)
  - Ermini, M., 1979 (Box 8)
  - Everitt, A., 1976 (Box 8)
  - Ewing, J.R., 1986 (Box 8)
  - Executive Officer, National Institute on Aging, 1975-1976 (Box 8)
  - Exton-Smith, A.N., 1979 (Box 8)
  - Fabregat, M., 1976 (Box 8)
  - Faiola, J., 1976 (Box 8)
  - Farah, A.E., 1975 (Box 8)
  - Farhi, L.E., 1985 (Box 8)
  - Finch, C.E., 1976-1987 (Box 8)
  - Finley, G.E., 1976 (Box 8)
  - Fishbein, M., 1976 (Box 8)
  - Fitzgerald, R., 1976 (Box 8)
  - Flannery, J.G., 1976 (Box 8)
  - Flodin, N.W., 1988 (Box 8)
  - Florini, J.R., 1978 (Box 8)
  - Foley, J.J., 1946-1947 (Box 8)
  - Ford, A.B., 1985 (Box 8)
  - Fowler, N.O., 1976 (Box 8)
  - Fox, L.H., 1977 (Box 8)
  - Fozard, J.L., 1987 (Box 8)
  - Franzblau, C., 1976 (Box 8)
  - Freeman, J.T., 1976-1988 (Box 8)
  - French, W., 1976 (Box 8)
  - Friedan, B., 1978 (Box 8)
  - Friedel, R.O., 1976 (Box 8)
  - Froimovich, J., 1976-1985 (Box 8)
  - Furchtgott, E., 1976 (Box 8)
  - Gallagher, J.R., 1976 (Box 8)
  - Gantt, W.H., 1976 (Box 8)
  - Garcia-Bunuel, R., 1974-1976 (Box 8)
  - Garfinkel, D., 1985 (Box 8)
  - Garland, R.M., 1979 (Box 8)
  - Garn, S.M., 1976 (Box 8)
  - Gavrilov, L.A., 1979 (Box 8)
  - Geill, T., 1984-1985 (Box 8)
  - Gerbauckas, D., 1977 (Box 8)
  - Gerber, A., 1976 (Box 8)
  - Gerstenblith, G., 1976 (Box 8)
  - Giambra, L., 1976-1986 (Box 8)
  - Godfrey, D., 1977 (Box 8)
  - Goedhard, W.J.A., 1978 (Box 8)
  - Goldenberg, E.N., 1978 (Box 8)
  - Goldman, R., 1976 (Box 8)
  - Goodrick, C., 1976 (Box 8)
  - Gordon, H.A., 1976 (Box 8)
  - Gore, I.Y., 1974 (Box 8)
  - Gerontology Research Center Branch Chiefs, 1976 (Box 8)
  - Green, D., 1976 (Box 8)
  - Green, V., 1987 (Box 8)
  - Greenough, W.B., III, 1974-1976 (Box 8)
  - Gregerman, R.I., 1976 (Box 8)
  - Greulich, R.C., 1976 (Box 8)
  - Greulich, W.W., 1959 (Box 8)
  - Growth, 1974 (Box 8)
  - Gubrium, J.F., 1976 (Box 8)
  - Guest Scientists, 1974-1976 (Box 8)
  - Guidotti, G., 1976 (Box 8)
  - Gulliksen, H., 1976 (Box 8)
  - Haber, P.A.L., 1984 (Box 8)
  - Haerther-Cavanaugh, G., 1977 (Box 8)
  - Hager, L., 1984 (Box 8)
  - Haggerty, A.D., 1975-1976 (Box 8)
  - Halberg, F., 1976 (Box 8)